Guide to the Library Science Alumni Association records, 1894-1974 RG0029
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
Library Science Alumni Association records
1894-1974
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
George Washington University. Dept. of Library Science. Alumni Association
RG0029
2.5 Linear Feet
Collection includes correspondence, programs, agendas, publications, newsletters, biographies, newspaper clippings, alumni directory, and correspondence,
Restrictions on Access
Some records may be restricted.
Acquisition Information
Materials acquired through transfers from the Alumni Association for the Department of Library Science
Historical Note
The Library School at The George Washington University graduated its last class in 1941. The GWU Library Science Alumni Association continued to function until 1956.
Collection Scope and Content
Materials in this collection include four scrapbooks of the library science alumni association (and Luther Rice Society Award presented in 1972). The collection also includes correspondence, meeting minutes, obituaries, annual teas, photographs. The collection covers the years 1929 to 1956.
Collection Organization
Organized into three series: Library Science Department and Alumni Association, Scrapbooks, and Office files.
Scrapbooks; Photographs; Washington (D.C.); Meetings; Obituaries; George Washington University--Alumni and alumnae; Schmidt, A. F. W. (Alfred Francis William); George Washington University
- Library Science Department and Alumni Association, 1894-1974; RG0029 Series 1; 0.5 Linear feet (Box 1, Box 2)
  Scope and Contents note
  This series includes correspondence, programs, agendas, publications, and newsletters from the Library Science Alumni Association. Also, included are papers from the Library Science Department including biographies, newspaper clippings, brochures, alumni directory, correspondence, bibliography, tuition checks, GW Bulletins. These items cover the Library Science Department's history, course descriptions, graduate degree requirements, theses, tuition, faculty and the Library Science Club constitution. They range in date from 1894 to 1974.
  - Alumni - Library Science alumni, 1932-1967 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    General note
  - Alumni - Library Science alumni - correspondence, 1959-1970 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Alumni - Library Science Alumni - Dedication of Alfred F. W. Schmidt Memorial Room in the University Library, November 11, 1973, 1967-1973 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Alumni - Library Science alumni - meetings, 1936-1973 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Alumni - Library Science alumni - publications, 1936-1972 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Alumni - Library Science alumni - publications - GWU Library Science Alumni notes (series 1 #1 March 1935 - series 9 #1 May 1943), 1935-1943 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Library Science Department, 1899-11/1973 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Library Science Department Degrees Conferred, 06/12/1929-02/22/1938 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Library Science Department --Faculty, 01/03/1974 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Library Science Department - History [1/2], 1894-1972 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Library Science Department - History [2/2], 1894-1972 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Library Science Department - Theses, 09/09/1931-06/22/1971 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Library Science Department - Tuition, 09/09/1931-06/22/1971 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Scrapbooks, 1929-1972; RG0029 Series 2; 1.5 Linear feet
  This series contains four scrapbooks of the Library Science Alumni Association and the Luther Rice Society award presented in 1972. These records date from 1929-1972.
  - Scrap Book, Vol. I: The Library Science Alumni Association, 1929-1935 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Newspaper clippings; Prof. Schmidt's 1933 address to Middle East Library Association; Aug., 1933 edition of "Good Words;" April, 1935 edition of "D.C. Libraries"
  - Scrap Book, Vol. II: The Library Science Alumni Association, 06/1929-12/1935 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    Newspaper clippings; Oct., 1935, Jan., 1936, Oct., 1936 editions of "D.C. Libraries;" American Library Association's 85th Annual Conference, Official Program May, 1936; GW Alumni Review, Vol I and II 1936
  - Scrapbook: The Library Science Alumni Association, 1937-1941 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    Newspaper clippings; Jan., 1937, April, 1937, July, 1937, Oct. 1937, Jan. 1938 editions of "D.C. Libraries;" Works Progress Administration pamphlet, Oregon March, 1937; Department of Library Science Course Offerings 1938-1939; "Introductory Lectures on Psychoanalysis" by Dr. Robert Waelder, June, 1941 edition of "Social Hygene News and Views"
  - Scrap Book, Library Science Alumni Association, 1933-1957 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    Newspaper clippings; The Middle Eastern Library Association Annual Meeting, 1937; Programs for the Convention of the Inter-American Bibliographical and Library Association, 1942, 1946
  - Plaque, The Luther Rice Society, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    The George Washington University's Library Science Alumni Association induction into the Luther Rice Society
- Office files, 1925-1971; RG0029 Series 3; 0.5 Linear feet (Box 1)
  This series contains correspondence, meeting minutes, obituaries, annual teas, and photographs. This material dates from 1925-71.
  - Correspondence, 1925 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Officers, 1939-1940 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Attendance, Correspondence, Meeting descriptions, 1950-1951 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Attendance, Correspondence, Meeting descriptions, Nominating Committee, 1952-1953 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Attendance, Correspondence, Meeting descriptions, Obituaries, 1954-1955 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Attendance, Correspondence, Meeting descriptions, Photographs, 1956 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Attendance, Correspondence, Meeting descriptions, Nominating Committee, 1957 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Attendance, Correspondence, Meeting descriptions, Nominating Committee, 1958-1959 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Attendance, Correspondence, Meeting descriptions, Nominating Committee, 1960-1961 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Attendance, Correspondence, Meeting descriptions, Nominating Committee, 1962-1963 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Annual tea, Correspondence, Members, Nominating Committee, 1964-1965 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Annual tea, Obituaries, Nominating Committee, LC Bulletin, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Library Newsletter, Report of the Director, GWU Magazine, Exhibit, Correspondence, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Library Newsletter, Tea, Attendance, Obituary, Nominating Committee, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - GW Library Newsletter, Annual tea, Nominating Committee, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Luncheons, Nominating Committee, Articles, 1970-1971 (Box 1, Folder 16)